[Steamy's Carpet Care]
[Comparing different carpet cleaners]
It is important to choose the right carpet cleaning business
because it is the difference between destroying your carpet
or making your carpet look nice and clean.
The first question you should ask is
who is actually going to do the job.
Is the person a trainee, a student?
Or is he actually a certified technician?
A certified technician would have to pass training
and collect yearly points with IICRC.
That's an international organization that provides training worldwide.
The technician should show you a card like that,
showing what sort of training he did.
You should be asking the technician that comes to your house
what sort of method he is going to use to clean the carpets.
Well, there is the dry cleaning method.
There is the steam cleaning method.
Dry cleaning is actually a method that was created to compensate
on steam-cleaning in commercial properties.
When properties would get steam cleaned on a yearly basis,
the properties would still get dirty during that year.
So they brought the dry cleaning as a system
to maintain that carpet to look good between the two steam cleaning methods.
Did they move furniture when they cleaned the carpet
or they didn't move the furniture or just go around the furniture when they do the job?
One of the questions you should ask a carpet cleaning company
is how many jobs do they do a day.
If a company would say to you that they do any more than 4 jobs a day,
that means they're not going to take the time in cleaning your carpets.
They'll be rushing in and rushing out as quick as they can to get to the next job.
For a 3-bedroom house with a hallway and a living area,
it should take roughly about 4 hours to do.
It's highly recommended when you ask your carpet cleaning company
what sort of method they use and what sort of process they use
like vacuum the carpet with hospital-grade vacuum cleaners,
agitate the carpet, steam clean the carpet with a truck-mounted machine,
and dry the carpet with drying pads.
The final touch would have to be grooming the carpet.
When you groom the carpet, you're getting rid of all the marks
that the drying, agitation, and the steam cleaning would leave on the carpet
to make the carpet look like brand new again.
You should ask the company you're choosing
if they do provide a written 100% money-back guarantee
if you're not satisfied with the job.
A good guarantee from a carpet cleaning company
would be if you're not happy with the job
they'll come back and do the job again free of charge.
If you're still unhappy with the job,
you make this company pay for a different carpet cleaning company
to come back and clean your carpet.
Finally, remember, it's not just about the cost.
It's about taking care of your precious and expensive carpet.
[Steamy's Carpet Care]
[www.steamys.com.au][1300 881 110]